http://www.clark.edu/about/governance/policies-procedures/privacy_policy.php

Skip to main content
Visit our COVID-19 web pages to learn more about Covid-19 operations at the college.
Need help now? Visit our Virtual Support Center.
Public Records Privacy Protection Policy
Adopted by the Information Services Board (ISB)
Effective: June 16, 2001 | Updated: November 28, 2016
Thank you for visiting the Clark College Web site and reviewing our Privacy Notice.
This statement addresses collection, use and security of and access to information
that may be obtained through use of www.clark.edu. This notice covers the following topics:
Information Collected and How it is Used
Information collected if you only browse this site.
If you do nothing during your visit to our Web site but browse, read pages, or download
information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information
does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following
information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address
is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet Service Provider (ISP)
or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol address to direct Internet
traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your
service provider (e.g. xcompany.com or yourschool.edu);
The type of browser and operating system you used;
The date and time you visited this site;
The web pages or services you accessed at this site.
The website you visited prior to coming to this website, if you clicked on a link
to take you here (referring sites or links).
What we collect if you volunteer information
The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by Clark College
only to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people
are using our services. Clark College analyzes this information (the Web site logs)
to determine how our Web site is being used, so that we may continually improve the
site's usefulness to the public.If, during your visit to our Web site, you participate
in a survey, send an e-mail, or perform some other transaction on-line, the following
additional information will be collected:
The e-mail address, and contents of e-mail, for those who communicate with us via
e-mail.
Information volunteered in response to a survey.
Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose.
The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio,
video, and graphic information formats you send us.
We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address
issues you may identify, to further improve our Web site, or to forward the e-mail
to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used for research
and enhancement purposes. Information from other on-line forms is used to fulfill
student requests for information and/or services.
Personal Information and Choice
"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable
to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's
name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not
considered personal information.You may choose whether to provide personal information
on-line.
We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to
us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an on-line form.
You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide
any personal information using an on-line form. Your choice to not participate in
these activities will not impair your ability to browse www.clark.edu and read or
download any information provided on the site.
If you choose not to use e-mail, participate in a survey or use an on-line form, you
will be provided with alternative contact methods.
If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, state
law and the Federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information
is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and
copying if not protected by federal or state law.
If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than
what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Registrar as shown in the Agency
Contact Information section of this statement.
The Clark College Web site is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect
any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of
personal information requested from or volunteered by children on-line or by e-mail
will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public
access.
Public Access to Information
All of the information collected at this site becomes public record that may be subject
to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists.
RCW 42.17. 260(1) states thatIn the State of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open
and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed
by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right
to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals.
Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.
Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection
and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions
of subsection (6) of this section (RCW 42.17.260(6)), RCW 42.56.210, 42.17.315, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or
records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy
interests protected by RCW 42.56.210 and 42.17.315, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with RCW 42.56.210 and 42.17.315 when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the
justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.
In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act
or other law governing the agency's disclosure of records, the Public Records Act
or other applicable law will control.
Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information
You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the Web-enabled
applications that are described below:
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
pay tuition and fees over the Web. The information is required in order to verify
your identity and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose
not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable
to apply tuition and fee payment over the Web, and you will have to pay your tuition
and fees in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally,
Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially
requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major
fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight
and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received,
the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student,
and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA) Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients;
(ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration
dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose
of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law.
Degree Audit
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
perform a degree audit of your records over the Web. The information is required in
order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but
if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display a degree audit of your
records over the Web, and you will have to request a degree audit in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally,
Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially
requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major
fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight
and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received,
the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student,
and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Financial Aid Inquiry
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
obtain your financial aid status over the Web. The information is required in order
to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you
choose not to provide it, we will be unable to give you your financial aid status
over the Web, and you will have to obtain this information in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally,
Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially
requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major
fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight
and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received,
the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student,
and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information
is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance
with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime
Learning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose
not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information
and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records either in
person or by mail.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Registration
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
register for classes over the Web. The information is required in order to verify
your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not
to provide it, you will be unable to register for classes over the Web, and you will
have to register for classes in person or by mail.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Registration Appointment
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information is
required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your registration
appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration
appointment information either in person or by Touch-tone access.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Schedule Planner
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
check requisites while using the schedule planner. The information is required in
order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide this
information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to verify your
eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling
into those classes.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student Address Change
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
change your address over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your
identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to
provide it, we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will have
to change your address in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student PIN Change
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
change your personal identification number (PIN) over the Web. The information is
required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to change your PIN over the
Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student Schedule
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify your
identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to
provide it, we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and
you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Unofficial Transcript
Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to
view your unofficial transcript over the Web. The information is required in order
to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you
choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript
over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal
information about you except for directory information. Only directory information
can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order
to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education
information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records
and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to
a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information
is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of
birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and
sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees
and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended
by the student, and other similar information.
Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.56.210 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
(a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients
or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information
You can review any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using
the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable
information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly
shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identify before
granting access or making corrections. (RCW 43.105.310)
Security
The Clark College website has many links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses.
When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Clark College website and
this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject
to the privacy policy of that new site. Clark College takes precautions to safeguard
personal information you provide through our web services.
This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or
other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via
the Clark College website.
Disclaimer
Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State
of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information
published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services
linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance
on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information
may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information
obtained from this system does so at their own risk.
Clark College reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time
by posting such revised Privacy Notice on the Clark College home page.
Contact Information
You may contact Clark College as follows:
To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information:
Registrar Clark College 1933 Fort Vancouver Way  MS 21 Vancouver, WA 98663-3598 360-992-2876 FAX 360-992-2183 registration@clark.edu
To offer comments about Clark College's website, or about the information presented
in this Privacy Notice:
Web Development Clark College 1933 Fort Vancouver Way MS 02 360-992-2891 FAX 360-992-2549 webmaster@clark.edu
Catalog (Current)
Catalog (Archive)
